Mr. Tosaka.
登坂社长
How are you finding your new full-commission employee?
我介绍的那位自由中介 您还满意吗？
As expected,
正如所期
he's quite the go-getter.
他是个非常有行动力的人
Thank you.
多谢了
I hope the tiger isn't too aggressive in this Tiger Balm.
希望不会适得其反
-Kiriyama. -Yes?
-桐山 -嗯？
Thank you for everything thus far.
谢谢你迄今为止所做的一切
How can I ever repay you?
我该怎么报答你？
Well,
这个嘛
perhaps you could order me something sweet from here, like--
要不您请我吃这里的甜品吧 比如…
Sorry to keep you waiting.
抱歉让你久等了
I didn't realize.
原来两位有约了
Please. Take your time.
请慢慢聊
Kiriyama.
桐山
QUEEN OF REAL ESTATE MADAM
（房产女王 夫人）
Was it something I said?
是因为我说了什么吗？
He must have taken it the wrong way.
他肯定误会了
Of course.
可不是吗
Here. Have a seat.
来 坐吧
How is he, by the way? That boy of mine.
对了 我送去的那孩子还好吗？
How is Kento doing?
我是说健人
KENTO TOKAGE GEN Z SALES
（十影健人 Z世代销售）
So you've been accepted into Hitotsubashi University.
您将要入读一桥大学
In that case, I'd recommend this property, as it has no transfers for your commute.
那样的话 我推荐这处房源 交通方便 无需换乘
That's nice,
确实挺好的
but I'd really like to live in Yaoki while I'm in Tokyo.
但我已经决定 如果来东京 就要住在八起这边
I used to come here a lot when I was in Saitama.
以前我在埼玉县时 经常来这里
FIVE MINS. ON FOOT FROM YAOKI STATION
（步行五分钟 直达八起站）
Sorry to be a bother.
抱歉给您添麻烦了
FIRST YEAR COLLEGE STUDENT RENTAL CONSULTATION
（大学新生租房咨询）
Please, take all the time you need to consider your first solo apartment.
这是您首次独自生活 请慢慢考虑 时间不是问题
I knew it!
我就知道
You have a good eye!
您眼光真好
KEISUKE KUROSU REAL ESTATE SALESMAN
（黑须圭佑 房地产销售）
I knew this would be a winner.
我就知道您一定会喜欢这里
Perfect for your first time on your own, and Mom can rest easy.
您第一次自己出来住 这里非常合适 妈妈大可放心
I knew it!
果然
See, Mom? Mr. Kurosu says it's fine.
妈妈你看 黑须先生也说没问题
A big, obnoxious voice isn't going to persuade them.
聒噪的大嗓门可无法说服人家
I agree!
我同意
-I want her somewhere safe. -Of course.
-我也想让她住得安全点 -当然
It's over budget, but please?
有点超出预算 但拜托了？
Shall I arrange all the paperwork?
那么我去准备各种资料了？
-Let's do it! -Hooray!
-好的 -耶
He did it!
居然成功了
-Here. -Thank you.
-来 -谢谢
Right. I've made up my mind.
好 我决定了
Great.
您请说
Can we see it again?
我们再去看看好吗？
Okay.
好
Dang, how can I make him make up his mind?
该死 到底怎样才能让他下定决心？
Consider it from the money side of things.
如果只考虑价格
They're all within your budget,
这几处的租金全都在您预算之内
but in terms of facilities and proximity to the station,
但如果考虑到设施和到车站的距离
will you find something better than this?
您还能找到比这里更适合的房子吗？
Because I think you will.
我觉得能
I've handpicked all of these properties,
这些房源都是我亲自挑选的
but I won't stop until you're satisfied
但只要您不满意 我就会继续寻找
so let's get out there and see more properties!
所以 咱们去寻找更多房源吧
Come on. Let's go.
走吧
What?
嗯？
RENTAL APARTMENT AMBITIOUS YAOKI
（招租 八起公寓）
I just need one more month.
再给我一个月就好
Then I'll be able to back pay for two months.
到时我就能凑够两个月房租
CONSULTATION REGARDING RENTAL ARREARS
（拖欠房租 咨询）
Two months?
两个月？
I got a new job, so I promise!
我又找到一份新工作 保证没问题
Miss Kiyokawa.
清川小姐
Can you tell me why you're three months in arrears?
您到底为什么欠了三个月的房租？
I thought everything was all right when I found this place for you.
当初我帮您找到这房子时 好像没什么问题啊？
ASUMI KIYOKAWA THEATRICAL PERFORMER
（清川明日美 剧团演员）
I couldn't get enough hours at work until just last month.
上个月之前 我一直忙于排练 凑不够工时
LIAR ROMEO AND HONEST JULIET
（骗子罗密欧和正直茱丽叶）
Don't tell me…
难道…
It's you!
这是你
You're with Honnami Theater?
你登上本并剧场的舞台了？
Yes, but it's only a minor role.
对 但只是个小角色
You said you'd always dreamed of performing with Honnami Theater.
你之前说过 一直梦想着在本并剧场表演
That's why you came to the big city.
所以才来到大城市
I'll bet your parents are thrilled.
你父母一定很高兴吧
Yeah.
是的
They've always had your back.
他们一直在背后支持着你
I've got a long way to go.
我还有很长的路要走
I've finally got another big audition lined up.
最近终于又拿到了 一次重要的试镜机会
And so,
所以
I can't lose my home right now.
我现在不能失去这房子
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
What's up, Tsukishita?
怎么了 月下？
Well…
呃…
I just had an arrears consultation.
刚有租户因为拖欠租金的事找我咨询
It's an all-inclusive studio apartment at 59,000 yen a month.
是一套单房公寓 租金包含了管理费 每月五万九
AMBITIOUS YAOKI RENT 59,000 YEN
（八起公寓 租金59000日元）
It's a great property, the best in the area,
房子很棒 是那片区域里最好的
but the tenant is now three months in arrears.
但租客目前已拖欠了三个月房租
I see.
这样啊
And beyond three months, the owner can issue eviction proceedings.
超过三个月的话 房东就可以提出驱逐要求了
They're not in a good place right now.
他们现在情况不乐观啊
EVICTION PROCEEDINGS
（要求驱逐）
COURT GETS INVOLVED IN ORDERING A TENANT TO VACATE
（法院介入 勒令租户搬出）
I want to be able to help.
我想帮忙
It's just that "customer first" is very hypocritical.
你的“顾客至上”太虚伪
No.
别乱想
I'll do my best.
我得加油
Hello?
您好？
Yes, it's good to hear from you.
是 很高兴接到您的电话
Yes.
是
And that's a done deal!
又成了一单
KEISUKE KUROSU
（黑须圭佑）
-Wow. -Impressive.
-哇 -厉害
Nagase. Better watch your back or you'll lose the upper hand.
永濑 别掉以轻心 小心被黑须反超
That's full commission for you right there.
这就是他们自由中介的做事风格
-Full commission? -Yeah.
-自由中介？ -对
What's full commission?
什么是自由中介？
Full commission means everything I earn comes through commission.
意思是我不拿工资 收入全靠销售提成
Like a freelance partnership with Tosaka Real Estate.
类似于跟登坂不动产达成自由合作
That sounds like a sweet deal.
听起来不错呢
However, Kurosu must pay for all branded business cards out of his own pocket.
不过 跟各家公司合作的名片费用 都必须由黑须自行承担
Business gifts are also at his own expense.
如需送礼 也得他自掏腰包
If he wants to use our photocopier, that's 10 yen per page.
如果要用我们的复印机 费用则是每张纸十元
But here's the kicker!
话虽如此 最棒的部分来了
SALARY-BASED - FULL COMMISSION
（常规员工 自由中介）
Unlike us salary-based employees,
跟我们这些拿工资的常规员工不同
his income is capped only by his results.
他的收入上不封顶 完全取决于他的业绩
Compared to us, he gets a 60% commission on sales at Tosaka Real Estate.
相比我们 他在登坂不动产的销售 能提成60%
The sky's the limit!
根本没有上限
Or you could end up with nothing.
当然也可能颗粒无收
Of course, some of us are out there
当然 永濑你哪怕不做自由中介
enjoying the high-rise life, even without being on full commission.
也享受着摩天大楼的生活
Yeah, the high rise.
那又如何？
I'd love to see how you do it.
我想尽快见识下你的实力
I can do it whenever--
我想什么时候就…
Say it, hero.
说啊 英雄
Not so straight and narrow now, are you?
这下你正直不了了吧？
Tell him, Nagase!
告诉他啊 永濑
I'll get there soon, you'll see.
我很快就让你见识 等着瞧吧
Hello, Saichi Nagase from Tosaka Real Estate.
您好 我是登坂不动产的永濑财地
You should think about full commission, Tokage.
十影 你该考虑做自由中介
Buy yourself a watch, a car, whatever you like.
给自己买块名表 或是豪车 什么都行
And just watch all the girls flock to you.
然后就坐等女孩们蜂拥而来吧
I don't care about that.
我不在乎那些
But…
不过…
This will be your second viewing.
这将是您第二次看房
I'll lock it in.
好的 我会安排时间
I'd like to schedule a time to speak directly with the owner.
我想预约直接跟房东面谈
Sounds like time well spent.
看来大家都在好好利用时间
TIM - TIME IS MONEY
（TIM 时间就是金钱）
Major respect.
给你比赞
You know it.
你很懂
Finger snap? Really? Yes, well done.
响指？不是吧？好吧 好样的
THE HONEST REALTOR 2
电视剧名：正直不动产2
Here. Leaflets for our newest additions.
给 这都是我们最新房源的传单
Give them a good check.
好好看看
EP 6 OF 10 COMING INTO FULL BLOOM
第6集：春天来了
All the first-year students and new employees come out in the spring.
春天来了 大学新生和职场新人 都会出来找房子
Can't this all be digital?
不能弄成电子版吗？
Who uses paper anymore?
现在谁还用纸质版啊？
The real estate industry
房地产行业
stands resolute in its old, fuddy-duddy ways.
要坚持它古板的昭和作风
Listen up.
听好
These leaflets
这些传单
are a sacred relic of the ingenuity of realtors over the decades!
都是房产中介们数十年来智慧的结晶
Only paper can give you that certain sense of warmth!
这种温暖 只有纸张才能提供
The age of analog is not over yet!
非数字的时代还未结束
Hey, Nagase, can I ask you something?
永濑 我能问你点事吗？
One of my landlord friends is in a bind.
我有位房东朋友遇到点麻烦
It seems one of his tenants is constantly in arrears.
他有一位租户好像一直在拖欠房租
He wants the money, or he wants them out.
他想收钱 不然就希望他们滚蛋
RENTAL PAYMENT HISTORY
（房租交纳记录）
Either way, he wants this resolved as soon as possible.
无论怎样 他希望这事能尽快解决
Can't the rental guarantor company handle it?
租赁担保公司不能处理吗？
Well, this guy's pretty old-fashioned.
我这个朋友很老派
He approved the rental agreement
当时对方找了亲属做担保
with just a relative as guarantor to bypass a guarantor company.
他就同意了 没找租赁担保公司
What is this landlord, a dodo?
这房东是已经灭绝的渡渡鸟吗？
Can you help me, Nagase?
永濑你能帮帮我吗？
Well…
这…
Mr. Nagase.
永濑前辈
I need your advice.
我果然还是需要你的建议
First him, now you.
你们接二连三的是怎么回事？
I'm about to go and see the landlord for that client of mine who's in arrears.
我之前说有个租户拖欠房租 我要去见那位房东了
In arrears?
拖欠房租？
May I ask which property it is?
我能问问是哪处房源吗？
It's Ambitious Yaoki.
八起公寓
Ambitious Yaoki?
八起公寓？
That's it, Nagase!
就是那里 永濑
The owner is Mr. Inoguchi. He's the one I need to help.
业主是猪口先生 我要帮的就是他
What?
啊？
This is perfect! Two birds with one stone.
太好了 一石二鸟
How is this perfect?
哪里好了？
The landlord and the tenant are at complete odds with each other.
房东和租客是完全对立的好吗？
What do you mean?
你们在说什么？
I see how it is.
我明白了
You knew Tsukishita would take the tenant's side,
你早就知道月下会站在租户那边
and you knew it would complicate things so you come crawling to me.
也知道这会让人夹在中间很难办 所以你就来找我了
Nagase. You owe me a favor, remember?
永濑 你还欠我一个人情 记得吗？
I can introduce you to someone who may like to purchase the Omiya property.
我可以为两位介绍一个人 他也许愿意买下大宫站的房子
You owe me one.
你欠我一次
So,
所以…
does this mean you'll help?
这是不是说明你会帮忙呢？
Thank you so much.
太感谢了
Appreciate it.
拜托了
We've gotta try.
我们总得试试
HARUKAZE BENTO - FRESH AND DELICIOUS LUNCHES TO GO
（春风便当 新鲜美味的外卖午餐）
Hello!
欢迎光临
One Harukaze Bento.
一份春风便当好了
Got it.
好的
-Here you go. -Thank you.
-请慢走 -谢谢
Have a great day!
感谢惠顾
-Asumi. -Yeah?
-明日美 -在？
Go take your break.
你去休息吧
Sure.
好
Hey, what happened with your rental?
对了 你的房租怎么样了？
My realtor's a big help. She said she'll fix it for me.
我的中介帮了我不少 她说会帮我解决
Thank goodness for that!
那真是太好了
I'm rooting for you!
我支持你
Thank you.
谢谢
If you could just grant Miss Kiyokawa one month's grace,
只要您再宽限清川小姐一个月
she said she'll be able to pay back two months' rent.
她说能一次付清两个月的房租
HISAO INOGUCHI OWNER OF AMBITIOUS YAOKI
（猪口久远 八起公寓房东）
Another month to pay two?
宽限一个月才付两个月房租？
She's already three months late.
她已经欠了三个月的钱
Are you able to be just a little more patient?
请您再耐心些好吗？
Well,
其实呢
I do like the idea of kids chasing their dreams.
我挺喜欢年轻人追逐梦想什么的
I could wait.
我可以再等等
Then you understand!
这么说来 您愿意理解她？
You know,
说起来
friends have told me I'm too nice to people.
朋友们都说我为人太善良
I only get by on what people pay me in rent these days.
我如今只能靠租户们交的租金度日
So, which is it?
他想怎样？
If your tenant is more than three months in arrears,
如果您的租客拖欠房租超过三个月
and if you've sent a final notice by registered mail and they still can't pay,
哪怕您用挂号信发出最后通牒 他们仍然无力支付
you are within your rights to evict her through the courts.
那么您就有权通过法院将他们驱逐
Hey.
喂
Why would you say that?
你说这个干什么？
I said it to Mr. Fujiwara myself.
我已经跟藤原先生说过了
I'd hate to have to evict a guest through the courts.
我不想通过法院驱逐客人
GUEST = TENANT
（客人=租户）
-So, which is it? -Which is it?
-他想怎样？ -到底怎样？
Well, I'm supposedly a very generous man,
按说呢 我是个非常慷慨的人
but I'm also a man who does things the old-fashioned way.
但我也是个用传统方法做事的人
I get you.
我懂
You don't wanna lose out, and you don't wanna lose face.
你不想损失钱财 也不想丢了脸面
You worry about what people think.
你很在意别人的看法
What did you say?
什么？
Tokage, how could you say that to Mr. Inoguchi…
十影 怎么能跟猪口先生说这种话…
He didn't mean--
他不是那个意思
…before I got a chance to say it myself!
…害我都没机会亲自说了
-Mr. Nagase! -I'm right, aren't I?
-永濑前辈 -我说得对吧？
Nobody who's generous goes around calling themselves generous.
真正慷慨的人 才不会到处宣扬自己很慷慨
Mr. Tokage! Be quiet!
别说了 快闭嘴
Yes. Zip it, and let me have a turn.
没错 赶紧闭嘴 轮到我来说
-What? -Mr. Inoguchi.
-嗯？ -猪口先生
Are you familiar with this old saying?
您听过这句老话吗？
"Lord as to the serf.
“房东如父母
Landlord as to the renter," or here, your "guest."
租户如孩子” 或者用您的话说 “客人”如孩子
This saying has existed since the days of yore.
这句老话 自古有之
Yes, I know it!
我当然知道
Back then, landlords took responsibility for the young people in their care.
过去 房东需要 对住在自己屋檐下的年轻人负责
They were concerned for their grades, employment, and fiscal standing!
要操心他们的学业 工作和财务状况
But you, you're evasive and only concerned about your own standing!
而你却回避责任 只考虑自己
You? A landlord? Fat chance!
就你还自称房东？醒醒吧
That's it!
够了
Now I don't even want her money!
她现在给钱也没用了
Now, I want her out!
我要她搬走
Please, Mr. Inoguchi--
别这样 猪口先生
Don't like it?
不愿意吗？
Then make her pay up everything she owes right now!
那就让她现在立马还清所有欠款
AMBITIOUS YAOKI
（八起公寓）
I know, but I'm not a child anymore, Ma.
我知道 妈 可我已经不是小孩子了
FRUITS FROM HIROSHIMA
（广岛水果）
I can buy these things myself.
这些我可以自己买
You don't need to worry about me.
您不用为我担心
I'm not pushing myself too hard.
我没把自己逼得太紧
And what about you?
您怎么样？
GOOD LUCK, ASUMI! MOM'S ROOTING FOR YOU
（明日美 加油 妈妈支持你）
Are you doing well?
还好吗？
HARUKAZE BENTO
（春风便当）
Here you go.
请慢走
-Thanks. -Have a great day!
-谢谢 -感谢惠顾
-Asumi. -Yeah?
-明日美 -在？
-Can you get the fryer? -Sure.
-把鸡肉拿过来好吗？ -好的
Sorry, please wait.
抱歉 请等候
Thank you. You may proceed.
抱歉 请通行
Thank you.
谢谢配合
Miss Kiyokawa couldn't get any time off work again today.
清川小姐今天不能再请假了
Just call and explain everything for now.
先打电话过去解释一下吧
It's up to her to decide.
看她怎么决定
But we really should speak in person for this.
可这种事应该当面说吧
We're breaking some terrible news to her, after all.
毕竟是要告诉她坏消息
Shall we try and visit her at night then?
那…要不我们今晚去拜访她？
I don't do overtime.
我不加班
Mr. Tokage.
十影
Miss Kiyokawa is working day and night to pay back what she owes.
清川小姐为了还清拖欠的房租 没日没夜地工作
What's one day of overtime to you?
你加一次班怎么了？
It's all right.
算了
Didn't you ever hear the story of The Ant and the Grasshopper?
你没听过蚂蚁和蚱蜢的故事吗？
And?
什么？
The grasshopper was all vibes…
蚱蜢只想躺平…
VIBE = CHILL OUT
（躺平=放松）
…and so the hardworking ant won.
…于是努力工作的蚂蚁获胜了
I'd say I'm the ant here.
这样的话 我觉得我才是蚂蚁
How?
啊？
I clock out on time every single day.
我每天都按时上下班
Your client is off chasing some fanciful dream,
而你的客户却在追逐不切实际的梦想
working on-and-off hours at dead-end jobs.
没日没夜地从事毫无前途的工作
Isn't that what a grasshopper would do?
这不正是蚱蜢会干的事吗？
Whatever.
懒得理你
There they go again.
又来了
Putting out fires is the biggest waste of time.
帮客户收拾烂摊子 才是最浪费时间的事
Yes! Major respect.
没错 大大比赞
Excuse me.
打扰了
Mr. Kurosu, you have a complaint.
黑须先生 有客户投诉您
A complaint?
嗯？
You too, Mr. Nagase.
人家也投诉永濑先生
What's wrong?
什么？
We went to the same cram school.
我们以前是补习班的同学
Now we're in the same college.
现在又进了同一所大学
We were excited to be living in Tokyo together…
我们得知对方也在东京找到了住处 都很激动…
KIICHI KATAGIRI CRAM SCHOOL CLASSMATE
（片桐纪一 补习班同学）
NAGASE'S CLIENT KUROSU'S CLIENT
（负责人：左永濑 右黑须）
…and then we found out we'd be in the same building.
…然后我们发现居然租到了同一栋楼
We'd both be paying 90,000 yen.
租金都是九万日元
So, why are our up-front costs so different?
那我们的前期费用 凭什么差别这么大？
QUOTE
（报价单）
Mine says I gotta pay some kind of brokerage fee.
我这份说 我需要支付什么中介费
99,000 (INCL TAX) KUROSU'S CLIENT
（含税99000 负责人：黑须）
0 - NAGASE'S CLIENT
（0 负责人：永濑）
Whoops.
糟糕
Allow me to apologize. This has clearly been my mistake.
非常抱歉 显然是我弄错了
Mistake?
弄错？
I'm so sorry to have made you come all this way.
抱歉让您大老远跑一趟
I will issue the refund immediately.
我立刻安排退款
If this is a mistake, then scam callers are simply calling the wrong number!
如果这只是简单失误 那电话诈骗犯也只是拨错了号码
Let me see.
我来看看
I knew it.
果然
I can tell you exactly why your up-front costs are so different
我能说明两位的前期费用 为何天差地别
despite having the same building, same layout, and same rent.
明明两位租的是同一栋楼 房间的布局和租金也完全相同
Please do.
请说
This leaflet contains all the information you need
这份传单包含了选择出租房源时
when selecting a rental.
需要知道的一切信息
This is what I gave to Mr. Aoe.
这是我提供给青江先生的
This is what you got, Mr. Katagiri.
而这份是片桐先生您拿到的
Can you spot the difference?
两位能看出有何不同吗？
YAOKI PARK MAISON
（八起公园公寓）
A PRIME LOCATION WHERE YOU CAN FULLY ENJOY STUDENT LIFE
（让您充分享受学生生活的 黄金地段）
AD: 200
（广告费：200）
It's here.
这里
It's an ad.
这份是广告
An advertising fee.
要收取广告费
Advertising fee?
广告费？
We call this an advertised property.
我们称之为广告房源
Let's break it down.
我来解释一下
An advertised property
广告房源
is one where a landlord or a company has paid a fee to the brokerage agency,
即房东或房产公司 需向中介支付一笔费用
almost like a "good luck" fee,
差不多相当于“好运”费
so that the agency can find a tenant as quickly as possible.
希望中介能尽快找到租户
The agency makes money from the agreement
中介可从协议中赚取利润
without having to charge the tenant any fees.
而无需向租户收取任何费用
That's why Mr. Aoe's quote doesn't have a brokerage fee.
所以青江先生的报价单里没有中介费
Mine doesn't have AD.
我这份传单上没有广告费
AD: 200 - NAGASE'S CLIENT KUROSU'S CLIENT
（广告费：200 负责人：上永濑 下黑须）
So, does that mean I also don't need to pay the fee?
那么 是不是说明 我也不用付中介费？
That's right.
没错
You did this on purpose.
你是故意的
Can you prove it?
你有证据吗？
I cannot.
没有
But if we look at your tablet…
但要是看看你的平板电脑…
You two! Stop that. You're with clients!
你们两个够了 客人还在呢
Sorry for that display.
让两位见笑了
I'm the Head of Sales here.
我是销售部长
I must apologize for that brazen display by my employees.
请允许我为手下的无耻表现 向两位道歉
Make sure you return the money.
一定把钱退给人家
-Sorry about that. -Whatever.
-抱歉了 -嗯
You photoshopped the leaflets, didn't you?
你修改了那些传单 对吧？
You did it so you could double your fees.
这样你就能两头收费
Even if that were true,
就算是真的
whether it's advertised or not,
不管是不是广告
there's no rule that says you can't take a brokerage fee.
都没有规定说不准收中介费
We try not to accept them for advertised properties!
我们尽量不收广告房源的中介费
Is that so?
是吗？
Thanks for the heads-up.
多谢提醒
Nagase, that's enough.
永濑 够了
Your clients are waiting.
你的客户还等着呢
Kurosu. Follow me.
黑须 跟我过来
Well, that was a waste of time.
真是浪费时间
You. Get out there and hand out some tissues.
喂 赶紧出去多发点纸巾
I'm on lunch break.
我现在是午休时间
-Look here-- -Mr. Nagase, that's harassment.
-你给我听好… -永濑前辈 这是职场霸凌
I mean, whatever.
随便吧
It's not like I've had a hard day.
反正今天不好过的又不是我
Glad you got a refund.
太好了 你拿到了退款
Good thing we're careful.
幸好我们够小心
What shall we do now?
我们现在干什么？
MONTHLY SALES PERFORMANCE GRAPH
（月业绩图）
Hanasawa. I see you're still hot on Kamiki's heels.
花泽 看来你还是紧咬着神木啊
NO.1 KAMIKI - NO.2 HANASAWA
（第一名 神木 第二名 花泽）
Were you aware of this, sir?
社长 这个您知道吗？
This is our reputation online.
事关我们的声誉
Kamiki may be bringing in the money, but he's damaging our reputation.
神木先生也许带来了不少业绩 可他也在破坏我们的声誉
LOAD OF GARBAGE CORRUPT - FRAUD
（一群垃圾 腐败 欺诈）
The best fighter in the ring isn't the strongest.
拳击场上最棒的拳手 往往不是最强壮的那个
It's the most famous.
而是名气最大的那个
So, what if we've got a bad name?
就算我们名声不好又如何？
These days, a bad name is better than no name.
这年头 坏名声总好过没名声
Come in.
进来吧
I have something for you.
我有消息要告诉您
Well then.
那好吧
Let's see who wins.
来看看哪样会胜出
A bad name.
坏名声
Or no name.
还是没名声
I'll leave our new Tachikawa store to…
我会把立川站的新商铺交给…
Here.
给
HARUKAZE BENTO
（春风便当）
Hello?
打扰了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
What can I get you?
请问需要什么？
I'd like a salmon rice ball, and a kombu rice ball.
我要一个三文鱼饭团 一个海带饭团
And I'll have a tea.
再来杯茶
Sure. Won't be a moment.
好的 马上就好
Two rice balls and a tea.
两个饭团 一杯茶
That'll be 465 yen.
一共465日元
Sure.
好的
Here you are.
请慢走
Thank you.
谢谢
Have a great day!
感谢惠顾
Cheer up, Mr. Nagase.
振作点 永濑前辈
Home time. See you.
回家时间到 明天见
-See ya. -Bye.
-再见 -嗯
Nagase. Nagase!
永濑
I'm going home on time today.
我今天要准时下班回家
Pack your things.
快收拾东西
Madam just called. She's invited you to dinner.
夫人刚打电话来邀请你去吃晚餐
Madam did?
夫人？
Mr. Nagase, come on.
永濑 来吧
-Is something wrong? -Miss Tsukishita, you go too.
-怎么回事？ -月下 你也去
Over there. Please, go ahead.
这边请
It's fine.
别紧张
-Mr. Tokage? -You have it.
-十影？ -你可以的
Do you think this is to find out how you've been training Mr. Tokage?
这不会是测试吧？ 要看看永濑前辈有没有好好训练十影
Could be.
有可能
Wow, that's good.
太好吃了
Do you often eat such lavish meals with Madam?
你经常跟夫人一起 吃这么奢华的晚餐吗？
Sometimes.
有时候吧
I have been stood up before.
他以前一直放我鸽子
Well, he is a very important person.
看来您真是很看重他呢
So I don't often get to hear how he's doing these days.
说起来 我最近不常听到他的消息
How is he at work?
他工作表现如何？
He's learning a lot from me.
他跟着我学了不少
I'm learning more from Kurosu.
我跟黑须先生学得更多
What ever do you mean?
这话是什么意思？
Kurosu doesn't waste his time.
黑须先生不浪费时间
Waste of time, waste of time.
张口闭口“浪费时间”
Kurosu cheated his client
黑须为了多赚顾客的钱
to get more money out of them.
不惜欺骗他们
You mean that complaint today?
你是说今天的投诉吗？
He can kick up a stink,
那人可以把事情闹大
but his rent and tuition will still come from daddy's pockets.
但他的房租和学费 仍需父母来掏腰包
That's no reason to crush people's dreams just as they come to the big city.
那我们也不该在人们初来大城市时 就摧毁他们的梦想
Dream, or whatever.
梦想什么的
He's the type to not even realize he's won the lottery of life.
他那种人根本不会意识到 自己其实中了人生彩票
I think it served as a good lesson.
我觉得这算是给他好好上了一课
Mr. Tokage.
十影
It's just as Mr. Nagase said.
就像永濑前辈之前所说
"Lord as to the serf. Landlord as to the renter."
“房东如父母 租户如孩子”
But that relationship has broken down these days.
但如今那种关系已日渐淡薄
It's up to us as realtors to come to the tenant's rescue.
得由我们房产中介来帮助租户
With our jobs, we can help people.
我们这份工作可以帮到别人
You can never really help someone, can you?
人永远无法真正帮助别人 不是吗？
That's not true.
才不是
I think we've killed the vibe here.
我们好像破坏气氛了
I'm leaving.
我先走了
Madam. Can I ask you something?
夫人 我能问您一个问题吗？
Why is Mr. Tokage such a little brat?
十影君到底为什么这么混蛋？
-I know he's Gen Z, but-- -Stop.
-我知道他是Z世代 可… -别说了
It's my fault.
都怪我
What?
嗯？
I don't mean to brag,
我无意炫耀
but Kento's grandfather, my late husband,
但健人的祖父 也就是我已故的丈夫
he was head over heels for me.
他生前对我一往情深
So much so that he even went into debt to spoil me.
甚至为了宠我 不惜举债
He didn't seem to care at all
他好像根本不在乎
for the son he'd had with his ex, or his son's family.
他跟前任所生的儿子 也不在乎儿子的家庭
I learned all this after the fact,
我是事后才知晓的一切
but apparently his son
但显然 他的儿子
had to deal with the aftermath of all of his debts.
当初不得不承受了他欠债的后果
Mr. Tokage! I know you're there. Pay up!
十影 我知道你在里面 快还钱
DUNNING LETTER
（催款令）
Kento's mother
健人的母亲
fell ill prematurely and passed away.
早早就病逝了
We'll be back.
我们还会再来
-I'm scared. -You better be ready!
-我害怕 -你最好做好准备
He lived alone with his father.
他独自跟着父亲生活
KENTO AND HIS FATHER
（十影父子）
Come on, Kento. Let's eat.
来 健人 我们吃饭
Kento's father had a positive attitude, and was a hard worker.
十影的父亲非常乐观 工作也很勤奋
They're gone now.
他们现在走了
-But he was never rewarded for it. -It's okay.
-但上天却从未因此而眷顾他 -没事了
Kento! It's all right, Kento!
健人 没事了
He passed away before he got that chance.
他没能等到那份眷顾就去世了
See?
好吗？
After that, Kento was shuffled from family member to family member.
之后 健人就辗转于不同亲戚家
I must have first met him
我第一次见到他
about two years ago now.
应该是两年前的事
I didn't know how to approach him.
我不知该如何与他亲近
I wouldn't be surprised
就算他恨我
if he resents me.
我也不会意外
But
可是
what if he resents his parents too?
如果他也恨他的父母怎么办？
I couldn't bear the thought.
我不敢想
I know he must be very difficult to handle.
我知道他一定很难管教
No.
不
I'll step up to the plate.
我会负起责任
I'll turn him into a real realtor.
把他变成一个真正的房地产中介
I promise.
我保证
I'll do my best too.
我也一定全力以赴
Thank you.
谢谢
Sorry, please wait.
抱歉 请等候
Come on through.
请通行
You may now cross.
现在可以通行了
Thank you.
谢谢配合
Sorry, please wait.
抱歉 请等候
Come on, I'm in a hurry.
不是吧 我赶时间
It won't be long.
抱歉
Have a great day.
感谢惠顾
Sorry, please wait.
抱歉 请等候
-How long is this going to take? -Thank you.
-还要等多久？ -抱歉
Gimme a break.
搞什么
Tokage.
十影
Miss Kiyokawa from Ambitious Yaoki has some time available.
八起公寓的清川小姐抽出了一点时间
We're going to discuss her late rent.
我们要去跟她商量拖欠房租的事
You need me too?
我也得去吗？
Of course we do.
当然
"Every one of us here is merely impersonating another.
“我们这里的每一个人 都只是在模仿他人
If that is discomforting, please just think of it as a dream."
如果你感到不适 请把这想象成一场梦”
"Every one of us…"
“我们这里的每一个人…
"Every one of us here is merely impersonating another.
“我们这里的每一个人 都只是在模仿他人
If that is discomforting, please just think of it as a dream."
如果你感到不适 请把这想象成一场梦”
Hello. Sorry to make you come out all this way.
抱歉让你们大老远跑一趟
It's fine.
没关系
We're not too far from my next shift here
这里离我接下来打工的地方不远
and I don't get much time to practice for my audition.
正好我没有太多时间准备我的试镜
About you being in arrears.
关于您拖欠房租的事
You have a parent as guarantor.
您当初找了父母中的一位作为担保人
Can you ask them to pay what you owe?
能不能让他们先帮忙垫付？
Sorry, that's all we could do.
实在抱歉 我们只能做这么多了
I know it's not what we wanted.
我知道这并不符合我们的预期
Unfortunately, as it stands,
但很遗憾 目前来看
you're only relying on the generosity of your landlord.
您只能寄希望于房东的慷慨宽限
I'm sorry.
抱歉
It may be that you'll need to move out
您有可能需要搬出去
and get back on your feet living with your parents again.
再次跟父母一起生活
My parents run a fruit farm in the countryside.
我父母在乡下经营着一家果园
If I'm being honest,
说实话
I have thought about
过去这一年
moving back in with them over this past year.
我其实多次想过 搬回去跟他们一起生活
They're getting old,
他们年纪大了
and I know they're struggling.
我知道他们挣钱也不容易
But then…
可是…
I got the part with Honnami Theater.
我之前得到了在本并剧院演出的机会
And my parents…
我的父母…
they were so happy for me.
他们无比为我高兴
I could tell they were crying
我打电话告诉他们时
as I told them over the phone.
能听出他们哭了
GOOD LUCK, ASUMI! MOM'S ROOTING FOR YOU
（明日美 加油 妈妈支持你）
I can't go back.
我不能回去
I've already decided this.
我已经决定了
Okay.
我明白了
I'll speak to the owner again.
我会再跟房东谈谈
Seriously?
不是吧
What a waste of time.
浪费什么时间
Miss Kiyokawa.
清川小姐
You're not paying your rent.
你连房租都交不起
You need to quit talking about your dreams and just get the hell out of there.
就别口口声声说什么梦想了 赶紧离开这里吧
You're just wasting all of our time here.
你这样只会浪费我们大家的时间
Mr. Tokage.
十影
I know you kids these days,
我了解你们现在这些小孩
I know you like to prioritize your time--
我知道你们都优先考虑自己的时间
But you sound like a dumb parrot squawking "waste of time, waste of time" on repeat!
但你张口闭口“浪费时间” 就像只笨拙的鹦鹉在学舌
On repeat!
学舌…
Many so-called "wastes of time" are, in retrospect, meaningful.
你所谓“浪费时间”的事 其实很多都颇有意义
We know this, but you're so scared to fail that you just turn tail and scram!
我们知道 你只是太害怕失败 于是选择逃跑
Someone like you…
像你这样的人…
I'll turn him into a real realtor.
我会把他变成一名真正的房地产中介
Thank you.
谢谢
…should just quit.
…还是赶紧辞职吧
Fine. I will.
好 我会的
What?
嗯？
Mr. Nagase! What about your promise to Madam?
永濑前辈 你之前是怎么跟夫人保证的？
Wait!
等等
Why should I give up on my dream just because I can't afford my rent?
凭什么我付不起房租 就该放弃自己的梦想？
What?
嗯？
Did I say that?
我有那么说吗？
Yes, you did.
你说了
I meant the opposite.
我本意是相反的意思
The opposite?
相反？
What I meant to say
我是想说
is you're better off leaving that place if you want to follow your dreams.
如果你还想追逐梦想 最好离开那公寓
Miss Kiyokawa.
清川小姐
You're working day and night just to pay back what you owe.
你为了还清房租 没日没夜地工作
Even that's not enough. You still owe money.
即便那样还是不够 你还是无力偿清
What's more,
不仅如此
you don't have any time to practice your performances.
你也没时间练习自己的表演
-Yes. -You're wasting your--
-对 -这就是浪费时…
Wait, maybe not.
等等 也可能不是那样
The landlord wants you out,
房东想让你搬走
and will forgive what's owed in order to get you out.
为此 他应该愿意 把你的欠款一笔勾销
So that only leaves one alternative…
那么就只剩一个替代方案了…
I get it.
我明白了
Thank you so much for clearing that up--
非常感谢你把话说清楚…
I take it back!
才怪
How's the client going to understand that?
客人怎么听得懂那些？
Use your words more.
多说人话
Don't just call things a waste of time!
别张口闭口只知道“浪费时间”
Let me translate for Tokage.
我来帮十影翻译一下
What he means to say is you should move out
他是想说 清川小姐你该搬出去
and find a cheaper place to rent.
租一个更便宜的地方
He means that is your only option here.
他想说 那是你现在唯一的选择
But it's not that the rent is unaffordable for Miss Kiyokawa.
但清川小姐也不是完全付不起房租
Only in accordance with the theory that rent should be one third of your income.
那是基于 “房租应只占收入三分之一”的理论
That theory is outdated.
那种理论现在已经过时了
Prices are always going up these days, but incomes aren't keeping up.
如今房租随时在上涨 而收入却没有相应增加
Rent going above one third of your income is absolutely possible!
房租超过你收入的三分之一 是完全有可能的事
One quarter.
四分之一
I recommend one quarter of your income.
我推荐你租只占收入四分之一的房子
That way, you can chase your dreams without being a prisoner to your rent.
那样的话 你就能追逐梦想 而不用沦为房租的奴隶
You need to balance your work time so you can devote yourself to the stage.
你得平衡好自己的工作时间 这样才能全身心地投入舞台表演
-Wouldn't you agree, Tokage? -That's right.
-是吧 十影？ -没错
But if she does that…
但如果那样…
I'd have to find a place in the 40,000 range.
我就得找一个租金四万左右的房子
There are plenty of places like that.
那种地方有很多
But,
可是…
she's female, so she has to consider things like security, for example.
她是女性 必须考虑安保之类的问题
I'm pretty sure I've seen some.
我肯定看到过一些
They'd be in those leaflets you made me memorize.
应该在你逼我背过的那些传单里
Wait.
对了
I remember when I was entering them into the computer today.
我想起来了 今天录入电脑时有一处
CHALEUR YAOKI
（八起沙勒尔）
There it is.
有了
STUDIO APARTMENT
（单房公寓）
It's far out, and the lighting is poor,
离车站很远 采光也不好
but it's recently renovated and not that bad of a place.
但最近翻新过 也没那么糟
It's also had new security cameras installed.
而且还新装了安保摄像头
45,000 yen, management fees included.
四万五 包括管理费
Yes. This is the one.
没错 就是这里
Ticks all the boxes.
满足所有需求
Thank you so much!
太感谢了
Hey, it's not that big of a deal.
倒也不至于…
You can stand up now.
快起身吧
What's wrong?
嗯？
I knew…
我之前就知道
it was too much to ask of you, Miss Tsukishita.
让月下小姐帮那种忙实在太过分了
But I didn't want to give up.
但我实在不想放弃
I couldn't tell my parents.
我没法告诉父母
I was a nervous wreck all day, every day.
每天都紧张不已
But now, thanks to you all…
但现在 多亏了各位…
I've never been so happy.
我真是太开心了
Thank you for all your help.
非常感谢各位的帮助
Take care.
保重
You too.
您也是
Good luck!
祝好运
Mr. Tokage.
十影
Thank you for helping Miss Kiyokawa.
你帮了清川小姐 谢谢
It's not like I wanted to help her.
我并不是想帮她
Then what did you want?
那是怎样？
I just think you should take care of your parents while you can.
我只是觉得 尽孝要趁早
If going after your dreams makes them happy, then…
如果追逐梦想能让父母开心 那么…
Make your parents happy?
尽孝？
I love it.
我喜欢
Well, you enlightened me on more than a few things today.
你今天给了我不少启发
Thank you.
谢谢
There, I said it.
我说出来了
I'll bet you think us Gen Zers are snowflakes that need to be coddled.
你肯定觉得我们Z世代 都是需要呵护的纸片人
I don't think that.
我没那么想
And I'll have you know, I cannot tell a lie.
我还要告诉你 我无法说谎
Well, it's home time.
回家时间到
I'll be leaving now.
我先走了
By the way, Tokage, what was it you said?
对了 十影 你之前说什么来着？
You quit?
你要辞职？
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天见
Overtime again for us?
咱俩又要加班了？
Yep.
对
I bet you also want to just get started on Miss Kiyokawa's new home too.
你一定也想 赶快操办清川小姐的新家手续吧
-Thank you. -Take care.
-谢谢 -保重
Sorry I couldn't take care of you.
抱歉当初没能对你们尽孝
But you really shouldn't have died on me so quickly.
但你们真不该那么早就离我而去
You know,
知道吗？
I never once felt like I'd been dealt a bad hand.
我从没觉得自己抽中了人生的烂牌
Not when you got sick,
妈妈生病时没有
or when those debtors were out to get you.
那些债主追着爸爸讨债时也没有
I was always happy by your side.
我在你们身边一直过得很开心
Mom, Dad…
妈妈和爸爸
I thought you were amazing.
我一直觉得你们很棒
Well, if you're not gonna eat 'em, I will!
你不吃的话 爸爸要吃了哦
You don't know what you're missing!
哇 超级好吃哦
Come on, eat up.
来 快吃吧
Good, right?
好吃吧？
Wow, yum!
嗯 好吃
"You should take care of your parents while you can."
“尽孝要趁早”
He said that?
他说了那种话吗？
Yes, and he helped out a client.
是的 而且他帮助了一位客户
Well, he did say he wasn't doing it to help her or anything.
不过他也说了 不是为了帮她什么的
You must be doing something right.
你一定做对了什么
I don't know about that.
我不敢邀功
He's in good hands with Tosaka Real Estate.
太好了 登坂不动产把他照顾得很好
-Cheers. -Thank you.
-干杯 -谢谢
Yes, I'll do my best too.
我也会尽力而为
-Tokage. -Yeah?
-十影 -在？
These are the new property leaflets.
这是新房源的传单
STUDIO APARTMENT FOUR MINS FROM TACHIKAWA STATION
（单房公寓 四分钟可达立川站）
THIS MONTH'S SLOGAN:
（本月口号）
BYE-BYE WINTER, BUY BUY PROPERTIES!
（寒冬拜拜 房子卖卖）
What a pointless waste of paper.
真是毫无意义的浪费纸张
Eventually, it all goes onto the tablet anyway.
反正早晚都要平板化
You really gotta get with the times.
你们真得与时俱进了
Paper has its advantages.
纸张也自有其优势
What?
嗯？
Here.
看
I've realized it's easier for clients to compare when they don't have to swipe.
我发现这样更方便客户比对 无需划来划去
True, but--
就算如此…
It's not pointless at all.
这完全不是毫无意义
It's a great time-saver.
反而能大大节省时间
Come on, stop bothering him.
好了 别烦他了
You'll waste his time.
别浪费他的时间
Your first overtime. Right, Mr. Tokage?
这是你第一次加班呢 对吧 十影？
It was only a little.
只加了一会
Nagase!
永濑
Miss Enomoto?
榎本小姐？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I have a request.
永濑 我有一个请求
Sure, anything.
当然 你尽管说
Will you
你能不能…
be my fiancé?
做我的未婚夫？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
My little girl has finally found herself a husband in Tokyo!
我的宝贝女儿 总算在东京找到了如意郎君
I'll buy her a high rise!
我要给她买一套摩天大楼的房子
So we can't do the contract without the deposit, can we?
您是说我如果无法支付订金 合同的事就别想了？
You should be proud to come in second.
你应该为得到第二名而骄傲
-What's that got to do with me? -What?
-跟我有什么关系？ -什么？
THE HONEST REALTOR 2 EP 6 - COMING INTO FULL BLOOM
电视剧名：正直不动产2 第6集：春天来了